은퇴 파티도 나쁘지 않네
It was a nice
retirement party.
그래
I guess.
하지만 로스만 교수님이
물러나게 한 건 너무해
Still, it's a shame
Professor Rothman was forced
to step down.
학교 측에서도 어쩔 수 없었지
What choice did
the university have?
정신이 나갔잖아
He snapped.
이론 물리학자들은
결국 그렇게 되지
It happens to theoretical
physicists all the time.
쉘든은 얼마나 남았을까
I wonder how long
Sheldon's got.
새우가 다 같은 크기네
These shrimp are
all the same size.
새우가 먹힐 순서를
논리적으로 정할 수가 없군
There's no the logical order
to eat them in.
얼마 안 남았을 거야
Can't be very long.
로스만 교수님 사무실이네
Hey, look, there's Rothman's
empty office.
슬프다
- Sad.
- Mm, indeed.
Yeah.
So sad.
찜
Dibs.
(tape measure retracting)
잘 지내?
What's up, fellas?
크립키,
여긴 어쩐 일이야?
What are you doing
here, Kripke?
새 사무실에 커튼을 달려고
사이즈를 재던 중이야
Ah, measuring my new office
for drapes.
새 사무실이라니?
This is not your office.
아직 배정되지 않았잖아
It hasn't been assigned yet.
지난 크리스마스 파티 때
Well, I called dibs
at the Christmas party
교수가 장난감함이랑 섹스를
시도해서 사무실을 찜해뒀지
when Professor Rothman tried
to have intercourse
with the Toys for Tots
collection box.
찜?
Dibs?!
여긴 놀이터가
아니라 대학이야
This is a university,
not a playground.
찜했다고 너한테
우선권이 있는게 아냐
Offices are not assigned
because someone called dibs.
너도 방금 그랬으면서
You just called dibs.
닥쳐
Shut it.
위계질서를 지켜야지
Offices are assigned
by seniority.
내가 먼저 학교에 왔어
I arrived
at the university first.
사무실은 내가 먼저 왔는걸
I arrived at the office first.
속담에 나오는
'얼리버드'가 바로 나야
I'm the proverbial early bird.
Gentlemen.
로스만 교수님
ALL:
Professor Rothman.
Good evening.
(others muttering
"Good evening" )
모자가 다시 유행이라 좋다
I'm glad
that men are wearing hats again.
품위 있어 보여
They're so distinguished.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
DC 기타 미국드라마 갤러리
The Big Bang Theory 5x17
The Rothman Disintegration
Original Air Date on February 16, 2012
자막 공대언니
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
작은 선물을 준비했어
I got you a little something.
작은 선물?
A little something?
Oh, it...
이건 너무 크잖아
Oh, this is huge.
네가 나한테 해준게 얼만데
What's huge is
what you've done for me.
에이미,
난 해준 것도 없어
Oh, no, Amy,
I haven't done anything.
널 만나기 전에는
소심하고 인기도 없었어
No, no, before I met you,
I was a mousy wallflower.
지금은 달라
But look at me now.
파티를 즐기는 도시 여자야
I'm like some kind of downtown
hipster party girl.
패거리랑 남자친구도 있고
With a posse, a boyfriend
앞쪽으로 후크를 채우는
레이스 브라가 생겼어
and a new lace bra that hooks
in the front, of all things.
뜯어봐
Open it.
그래
Okay.
갖고 있지 않는걸
주고 싶었어
I wanted to get you something
you didn't have.
Wow!
뭐라고 해야...
I... I don't know what to...
Wow.
마음에 들어?
Do you like it?
마음에 드냐고?
Do I like it? Wow.
어디다 걸어둘래?
So, uh, where are you
gonna hang it?
Oh, my God.
Hang it. Wow.
있잖아,
그러려면 준비를 해야해
Um, you know,
I'd have to go get a hook
못이랑 망치도 없고
and nails and a hammer and...
걱정 마
No problem.
Oh, look.
(laughs) You got...
다 준비해놨군
You just... you got it all
right there. Wow.
찾았어,
화장실에 계셔
I found him.
He's in the bathroom.
시버트 총장님
President Siebert?
나중에 말하면 안될까?
Can't this wait?
조금만 시간 내주세요
I'm sorry.
We just need a word.
나는 자네 상사고
성기를 잡고 있다네
Now? You realize I'm your boss,
and I am holding my penis?
쉘든, 프
라이버시 좀 존중해
Sheldon, give the
man some privacy.
죄송해요, 저 친구는
거리를 둘 줄 몰라요
I'm sorry. This guy's got
no respect for boundaries.
원하는 게 뭐야?
What do you want?
이 미친놈한테 알려주세요
Will you tell
this lunatic
로스만 교수님 사무실은
제가 쓰기로 했다고요
that Professor Rothman's
office is rightfully mine?
학과장과 상의하면 안 되겠나?
Can't you take this up
with your department chairman?
조교가 그러는데
안식년을 갖고 있대요
We tried. His assistant said
he was on sabbatical.
사무실 창문이 열고 닫히는
소리가 들리긴 했지만요
Although we distinctly heard
his office window open and shut.
자네들 때문에 편하게
일을 볼 수가 없잖아
Gentlemen, there's a task I'm
trying to accomplish here,
and I'm having
trouble doing it.
걱정을 끼치고 싶지는 않지만
Oh, my. President Siebert,
I don't mean to be an alarmist,
소변의 흐름이 감소된 것은
but difficulty initiating a
urine stream could be a symptom
전립선 비대증 증상이기도 해요
of benign prostatic hyperplasia.
원하신다면
If you're interested,
유튜브 동영상
링크를 보내드릴게요
I can send you a link
to a YouTube video
혼자서도 직장 검사를
할 수 있대요
that'll show you how
to perform your own rectal exam.
조언을 드리자면
우선 손톱을 자르세요
Uh, helpful hint--
trim your nails first.
못 들은 걸로 하세요
Ignore him,
President Siebert.
총장님처럼 젊으신 분이라면
I'm sure a young man such as
yourself has a perfectly...
전립선도 건강하겠죠
(pats)
healthy prostate.
사탕발림에 넘어가지 마세요
Oh, he's just trying
to butter you up.
참고로 말씀드리자면
And for the record,
검사할 때 버터를
윤활제로 쓰면 좋아요
butter is an excellent lubricant
for your rectal exam.
두 분이 알아서 해결하세요
Gentlemen, I'm going to allow
the two of you to work this out
두 분 모두
뛰어난 과학자이시고
because A) you're both
brilliant scientists,
사무실을 누가 차지하는지는
and B) as far
as who gets
눈꼽만큼도 관심 없어요
Rothman's office,
I couldn't give the furry crack
of a rat's behind.
여기까지 왔으니
Well, as long
as we're here,
나도 볼 일이나 봐야지
I might as well
take a leak.
크립키?
Kripke?
응?
Yes?
거긴 내 자리야
You're in my spot.
(both sigh)
진짜 크다
That is big.
완전
So big.
그리고 못생겼어
And ugly.
완전 추해
So ugly.
어떻게 해야하지?
What am I gonna do?
모르겠어
I don't know.
걸어두지 않으면
얼마나 실망하겠어
You can't take it down.
You'll break her heart.
저 얼굴 좀 봐
Look at that face.
저 큼직한 얼굴을
보면 마음이 심란해
That enormous, unsettling,
crazy face.
계속 보면 좀 나아질까?
Is there any chance
I'll learn to love it?
자신이 남자처럼 보이는
그림을 좋아한다면 가능해
That depends.
Do you like pictures of yourself
where you look like a man?
내려야겠다
All right, it's got to go.
에이미한테는
뭐라고 하려고?
What will you tell Amy?
이러면 어떨까?
How about I tell her
우리 둘만 그려서
네가 질투한다고
the painting makes
you feel jealous
because you're
not in it?
안돼,
나한테도 주면 어떡하라고
Nuh-uh. What if she gets me one?
베니스비치에서 하워드 엄마랑
레게머리를 하는 사진이 있어
I already have a picture
of me and Howard's mom
getting our hair cornrowed
in Venice Beach.
충분히 고통스럽다고
I've suffered enough.
에이미가 올 때만
걸어두면 되지만
Well, I guess I could
take it down and put it up
그러기에는 좀 무거워
when she comes over,
but it's kind of heavy.
그림처럼 힘센 남자가
아니라 아쉽다
Oh, too bad you're not as strong
as the dude in the painting.
이것 좀 봐
Would you look
at this?
이베이에서 어떤 꼬마한테
$25을 내고 주문한 거야
I paid $25
to some kid on eBay
손수제작한 해리포터
지팡이를 주문했는데
for a handcrafted
Harry Potter wand.
그냥 나뭇가지네
He sent me a stick.
뒷마당에서
나뭇가지를 주웠겠지
He went into his backyard,
he picked up a stick.
번호가 새겨있어
It's numbered.
한정판이군
Ooh, limited edition.
좋았어
Nice.
(knocking)
크립키일 거야
Oh, that'll be Kripke.
무슨 일인데?
LEONARD:
What's he doing here?
사무실 배정 문제를
신사답게 해결하려고
We're going to work this office
situation out like gentlemen.
그게 안 되면
차에 독을 타야지
And if that doesn't work,
I'm going to poison his tea.
- 쿠퍼
- 크립키, 들어와
Cooper.
Kripke. Come in.
차를 끓이고 있어
I'm making tea.
너도 마실래?
Would you like a cup?
그렇게 한가해 보여?
Am I wearing a
summer frock?
차는 됐고
No, I don't want tea.
본론으로 들어가자
Let's get down
to brass tacks.
우리 우정을 지키기 위해
Fine. In the interest
of preserving our friendship...
우리는 친구 사이가 아냐
We're not friends.
가슴 아프지만
사실이긴 하지
Well, that's a little hard
to hear, but all right.
너도 알겠지만
외교의 핵심은 타협이야
As you know, the essence
of diplomacy is compromise.
그 점을 염두에 두고
With that in mind,
다음과 같이 제안한다
I propose the following.
로스만 사무실은 내가 쓰고
I will take Rothman's office,
너는 받아들이는 거지
and you will find a way
to be okay with that.
사무실은 내가 쓰고
How about
I take Rothman's office,
넌 그냥 짜져 있을래?
and you go suck a lemon?
(airy laugh)
차 마시고 싶지 않아?
You sure I can't get you
that cup of tea?
가위 바위 보 도마뱀
스팍으로 정하면 어때?
How about
you decide this
with Rock-Paper-Scissors
Lizard-Spock?
그건 대체 뭐야?
What the frig is that?
인터넷 선두자 샘 캐스가
발명한 게임이야
Rock-Paper-Scissors-Lizard-Spock
was created
by Internet pioneer Sam Kass
as an improvement
가위바위보를 더
복잡하게 만들었어
on the classic game
Rock-Paper-Scissors.
샘 캐스 만세
All hail Sam Kass.
만세
ALL:
Hail.
어떻게 하는데?
How does it work?
간단해
Oh, it's very simple.
가위는 보자기를 자르고,
보자기는 바위를 감싸고
Scissors cuts paper,
paper covers rock,
바위는 도마뱀을 뭉개고,
도마뱀은 스팍을 독살하고
rock crushes lizard,
lizard poisons Spock,
스팍은 가위를 박살내고,
가위는 도마뱀을 죽이고
Spock smashes scissors,
scissors decapitates lizard,
도마뱀은 보자기를 먹고,
종이는 스팍을 반증하고
lizard eats paper,
paper disproves Spock,
스팍은 바위를 증발시키지
Spock vaporizes rock,
늘 그렇듯이,
바위는 가위를 부러뜨려
and as it always has,
rock crushes scissors.
다시 한번 말할래?
I'm sorry. Can you repeat that?
물론이지
Well, of course.
가위는 보자기를 자르고
Scissors cuts paper, paper
보자기는 바위를 감싸고
covers rock, rock
바위는 도마뱀을 뭉개고,
도마뱀은 스팍을 독살하고
crushes lizard,
lizard poisons Spock,
스팍은 가위를 박살내고
Spock smashes scissors,
가위는 도마뱀을 죽이고
scissors
decapitates lizard,
도마뱀은 보자기를 먹고
lizard eats paper, paper
보자기는 스팍을 반증하고,
스팍은 바위를 증발시켜
disproves Spock,
Spock vaporizes rock,
늘 그렇듯이
바위는 가위를 부러뜨려
and as it always has,
rock crushes scissors.
거의 이해했어,
다시 한번만
Almost got it.
One more time.
가위는 보자기를 자르고,
보자기를 바위를 감싸고
Surely. Scissors cuts paper,
paper covers rock, rock...
쉘든, 그만해
Sheldon, stop.
장난치는 거잖아
He's screwing with you.
그래?
Is he?
그렇다면
Well, then,
교착 상태에 이르렀군
it seems
we have reached an impasse.
결투를 신청하는 것
말고는 방법이 없네
I see no other option than
to challenge you to a duel.
장갑으로 한대 치고 싶지만
I'd smack you with a glove,
but just last week,
지난 주에
겨울 용품을 치워놨어
I packed away my winter things.
21세기잖아
It's the 21st century.
결투는 말이 안돼
You can't
have a duel.
잠깐, 하워드
H-Hang on, Howard.
배리, 총은 잘 쏘는 편이야?
Barry, how good
of a shot are you?
총이 아니라
두뇌 대결 말이야
Not pistols. Minds.
상식 퀴즈를 하자
A trivia contest,
분야는 네가 고르도록 해
and you may choose
the field of battle.
스타트렉 일반,
스타트렉 넥스트 제너레이션
Star Trek trivia, Star Trek:
Next Generation trivia,
스타트렉
딥 스페이스 나인
Star Trek: Deep Space Nine
trivia,
스타트렉 보이저
Star Trek:
Voyager trivia,
혹은 모형 기차
or model trains.
퀴즈에서는 네가 유리하지
You have a complete
advantage in trivia.
넌 직관상적
기억을 갖고 있어
You have an eidetic memory.
난 스타트렉을
안 본 지 오래됐어
Plus, I haven't watched
Star Trek
집 근처 스트립 클럽에
공짜 뷔페가 있더라고
since I discovered
the strip club near my apartment
has a free buffet.
둘 다 비슷하게
잘하는 분야는 없을 거야
LEONARD:
It's gonna be hard
to find something
you're both equally good at.
둘 다 비슷하게
못하는 분야는 있어?
Is there anything
you're both equally bad at?
운동
BOTH: Sports.
자, 1대1이야
All right,
this is one-on-one.
5번 성공하는 사람이
사무실을 갖게 돼
First person to five
wins the office. Any questions?
응, 쉘든
Yes, Sheldon.
5번이라니?
Five what?
농구대에 공을 넣으라고
Balls in the basket.
Ew!
(grunting)
아웃이지?
It's out, right?
타임
Time.
자리가 부족하네
Ran out of room.
학교에서 우리한테
장난치던 놈들 있잖아
You know all those
terrible things
bullies used
to do to us?
응
Yeah.
이젠 이해가 간다
I get it.
Ooh, aah!
Hey!
일부러 그런 거야
He did that on purpose!
아냐
No, he didn't.
너네는 일부러 뭔가를
할 수 있는 수준이 아냐
Nothing that's happening here
is being done on purpose.
1대1은 그만하고
Okay, uh, forget one-on-one.
자유투로 하자
Let's try
a free throw contest.
먼저 슛을 성공하는
사람이 이기는 거야
First person who makes a basket
wins the office.
너무 쉽게 만드네
Making it too easy there,
Hofstadter.
아니거든
No. No, I'm not.
Use the force
*스타워즈 대사
Use the force, Sheldon.
Use the force.
힘이 더 필요하네
I'm gonna need more force.
쿠퍼, 실망할 준비를 하시지
All right, Cooper, prepare
to have your heart broken.
(sighs)
저건 안 쳐주나?
Do I get points for that?
Oh!
(thud)
(panting)
(Sheldon and Kripke
gasping loudly for breath)
45분이나 썼다
All right,
we gave it 45 minutes.
이제 재미없어,
다른 걸 해보자
It's no longer funny.
Let's try something else.
떠오르는 거 있어?
What do you propose?
내가 셋까지 세면
Uh, on the count of three,
둘은 힘껏 공을 내리쳐
both of you bounce the balls
as hard as you can.
높게 튕기는 사람이 승자야
The highest bounce
wins the office.
넌 죽었어, 쿠퍼
Oh, you are going down, Cooper.
헛소리 하시네
I don't think so, Kripke.
고무공이라면
많이 튕겨봤거든
I've bounced many a rubber ball
in my day.
수다는 그만 떨자
All right,
that's enough trash talk.
하나
LEONARD:
One,
둘, 셋
two, three.
쉘든 공이 더 높아
Sheldon
was higher.
축하해
Congratulations,
쉘든, 네가 이겼어
Sheldon. You win office.
이래도 체육 과목에
불합격을 줄 거냐?
Who's unsatisfactory
in P.E. now?
♪ We go together
♪ Like rama lama lama
ka dinga da dinga dong ♪
♪ Remembered forever...
영화 정말 재밌다
Oh, what a great movie.
'그리스'를 본 적이 없다니
I cannot believe
you've never seen Grease.
엄마가 봇 보게 했어
My mother didn't allow me
to watch it.
내가 갱단에
가입할까봐 걱정하셨지
She was afraid it might
encourage me to join a gang.
가봐야겠다
I've got to go.
내일 일찍 일어나야 해
I've got to get up early.
고환에 영향을 안 끼치는
스테로이드가 들어왔는데
My company's testing
a new steroid
that supposedly
doesn't shrink testicles,
늦게 출근하는 사람이
크기를 재기로 했어
and the last one there
has to do e measuring.
나도 가야겠다
I guess I should get going, too.
잘자, 그림 속 페니
Good night, painting Penny.
잘자, 현실 속 페니
Good night, real Penny.
잘자, 현실 속 에이미
Good night, real Amy.
그림 속 에이미한테는
인사하지 않아도 돼
You don't have to say
good night to painting Amy,
영원히 곁에 있을 테니까
'cause she's never leaving.
잘자, 현실 속 페니
Good night, real Penny.
안녕
Bye.
잘자, 여장한 페니
Good night, transvestite Penny.
(sighs)
이제 좀 내려볼까
Okay. Let us take you
off the wall.
눈에서 멀어지면
마음에서도 멀어지지
Out of sight, out of mind.
제발 그랬으면
I wish.
아까 그 영화
좀 빌려도 될까?
You know, can I
borrow that movie?
노래 부르는 고딩들이
기억에 남네
Those singing hooligans
really got my motor running.
물론이지
Sure, sure. Enjoy.
다 보고 천천히 돌려줘
I mean, get it back
to me when you can, or...
아니다, 너한테 줄게
you know what, actually,
you keep it.
네게 주는 선물이야
It's just going to be
my gift to you.
- 안녕
- 고마워
- Bye.
- Thank you.
그림은 어디 갔지?
Wait...
Where'd the painting go?
저쪽에 있어
It's right over there.
왜?
Why?
나도 모르겠어,
이상하네
I have no idea.
That is weird.
- 싫어하는구나
- 아냐
- You hate it.
- No.
좀 커서 그래
No, no.
It's just, it's a little big.
- 난 정말 바보같아
- 아냐, 그렇지 않아
- I feel like an idiot.
- No, come on, you're not an idiot.
다시 걸어줘
Look, just help me
put it back up.
내가 가면 또
처박아 놓으려고?
Why? So you can just
take it down when I leave?
동정 따위는 필요없어
I don't need your pity.
Oh, Amy, come on...
조각품을 선물하지
않아서 다행이야
(choking up): I'm just glad I didn't
go for the sculpture.
전리품이로군
Ah, the spoils.
승자들이 열광하는
이유를 알겠다
I see why victors love them.
네가 이겨서 기쁘지만
I'm happy for you, Sheldon.
사무실을 따로 쓰게
돼서 조금 섭섭하네
But I have to admit I'm going to
miss sharing an office with you.
그렇겠지
Oh, of course you are.
아무때나 놀러와
Feel free to drop
by any time.
- 고마워
- 오기 전에 연락해
Thank you.
Yeah. Call first.
안녕
Oh. Hello.
로스만 교수님
Professor Rothman.
이젠 교수님
사무실이 아니에요
This isn't your
office anymore.
은퇴하셨잖아요
You're retired.
투명하다고
말하려고 한 거지?
I think the word you're
looking for is... "invisible."
사과하러 왔어
I came to say I'm sorry.
됐어
Don't bother.
- 에이미, 제발
- 너무 쪽팔려
Oh, Amy, please.
I'm so humiliated.
영화 보는 내내
그림을 보며 뿌듯했어
I sat there the whole time
that we were watching "Grease,"
thinking you liked the painting.
I know.
'썸머나잇'부터
'위 고우 투게더'까지
I was a fool from "Summer
Lovin'" to the very last
"rama lama lama ke ding
a de dinga a dong."
그래, 네 말이 맞아
You're right.
You're absolutely right.
처음부터 솔직하게
알려줘야 했어
I should have
been honest with you
선물이 너무 부담스러워
and told you
the gift was too much.
그렇겠지
Yes, too much.
우리 관계는 비대칭이잖아
Because our friendship
is fundamentally asymmetrical.
내가 훨씬 더 좋아하지
I clearly like you
more than you like me.
좋아하는 감정은
숫자로 나타낼 수 없어
I don't think you can
put a number on
how much one person
likes another.
1제곱미터 크기의
그림을 선물했잖아
I bought you a painting
that's 12 square feet in area.
숫자가 들어있어
There's a number.
에이미, 이러지 마
Amy, come on...
제곱미터가 싫으면
달러로 계산할까?
If you don't like feet,
you can try dollars.
3천 달러나 썼다고
The painting set me back
three grand.
Three gr... Oh, my God!
에이미
Look, look, Amy,
넌 소중한 친구라는걸
잊지 말아줘
all you need to know is,
you are my friend
널 잃고 싶지는 않아
and I don't want to
lose you out of my life.
미안한데 지금은
진심이 안 느껴져
I'm sorry, I'm just having
trouble believing you right now.
망치를 잡고 도와줘
Grab your hammer.
이미 상처 받았어
No. Damage is done.
이런 말 하고 싶지 않았는데
Okay, look, I didn't want to say
this, but the real reason
사실 그림을 내린 이유는
I took the painting down was...
베르나데트가
질투해서 그랬어
because it made
Bernadette very jealous.
세상에
Oh, my goodness,
왜 눈치를 못 챘지?
how could I have not seen that?
셋 중에 베르나데트가
제일 쿨하지 않은데
The painting is
a constant reminder
that of the three of us,
그 점을 상기시키는 그림이지
she is the least cool.
맞아, 바로 그거야
Yeah, that's...
that's what it is, so...
너무 착하다
You have such a good heart.
노력은 하지
Yeah... I try.
가자
Come on.
어디 가는데?
Whoa, whoa, where are we going?
너네 집에 그림을 걸어야지
We're going to go put
this painting back up
베르나데트는 어쩌고?
in your apartment.
Well, what about Bernadette?
같이 놀아주는 것으로
만족하라고 해
Oh, screw her. She's just lucky
we let her hang out with us.
(air conditioner blowing loudly)
뭐하는 거야?
What are you doing?
온도를 높이려고
I'm trying to raise
the temperature in here
젖꼭지가 옷을
뚫고 나오기 전에
before my nipples tear
through my shirt.
서모스탯을 쓰면 안돼?
Why don't you just
turn up the thermostat?
좋은 질문이야
Aha! Good question.
서모스탯이 옆방에 있을
거라고 누가 생각했겠어
It turns out the thermostat
for my new office
isn't in my new office.
No. It's next door,
대번포트 교수님 사무실인데
in Professor Davenport's office,
갱년기 발한을
즐기고 있어
who is currently
enjoying the hot flashes
associated with menopause.
여긴 왜 구멍이 있어?
Why is there a hole here?
사무실에 왜 구멍이 있냐고?
Why is there a hole
in my new office?
두 가지로 추려봤어
I've narrowed it down
to two possibilities:
누군가가 벽 안에 있던
뭔가를 갖고 싶어했 거나
"There was something in the wall
that someone outside
the wall wanted,"
더 소름끼치는 이유는
or the more disturbing,
벽 속의 무언가가
나가고 싶었다는 거지
"there was something
in the wall that wanted out."
그래도 창문이
열리는 방이잖아
Well, at least you
finally got a window that opens.
좋네
That's nice.
그래?
들어봐
Is it? Listen.
(wind chimes jangle faintly)
풍경 소리 싫어해?
What, you don't like
wind chimes?
질색이지,
그게 다가 아냐
No, I hate them,
but it gets worse.
(mockingbird whistling)
- 바로 저거야
- 새 소리?
- There it is.
- The bird?
불협화음이야
It's completely out of tune
with the wind chimes.
그래서?
So?
아직도 모르겠어?
You don't get it, do you?
저건 흉내지빠귀야
That's a mockingbird.
흉내지빠귀는
소리를 바꿀 수 있어
Mockingbirds can
change their song,
일부러 저러고 있어
which means he's
out of tune on purpose.
(mockingbird continues singing)
날 놀리고 있어
He's mocking me.
(rumbling)
저런, 너네도 느껴져?
Oh dear. There it is again.
Do you feel it?
네가 정신 나간
놈이란걸 깨닫고 있냐고?
The growing realization that
you are one wacky bastard? Yep.
아니, 진동 말이야
No. The vibration.
지질학 실험실 바로 밑이야
We are directly underneath
the geology lab,
체 진동기를 또 켰나봐
and they're running their
confounded sieve shakers again.
야, 자갈 원숭이들아
Hey, gravel monkeys,
돌대가리를 흔들어도
충분한 진동이 느껴진다고
if you need to shake rocks,
try jiggling your heads around!
쉘든, 진정해
Sheldon, relax.
어떻게?
How can I relax?
신경이 너무 날카로워졌어
My nervous system is
being stretched out
구멍에 새 소리에
like the strings of a harp
and plucked by holes and birds
로스만 교수님은
내쫓기 어려워
and wind and the
low-hanging scrotum
of the difficult-to-evict
Professor Rothman.
그렇게 불만이면
If you're not happy,
크립키한테 넘겨주면 어때?
why don't you just let
Kripke have the office?
그럼 내가 지는 거잖아
Wait, and let him win?
내가 미쳤냐?
Do I look crazy to you?
시끄러워서
생각을 못 하겠다고
(rumbling)
We're trying to think down here,
정동에 미친
광석쟁이들아!
you geode-loving
feldspar jockeys!
그리고 너
(mockingbird whistles)
And you...
정확한 음은
C, D, E, G, A야
the notes are
C, D, E, G and A.
또 틀리면
나무를 베어버릴 거야
You pick one or I am
chopping down that tree!
어때?
How's that?
오른쪽을 더 높게
Little higher on the right.
- 지금은?
- 조금 더
- Now?
- Little more.
이제 됐다
No. That's got it.
그러네
Yeah, okay.
That's, uh, that's good.
비밀을 말해줄게
I'll let you in
on a little secret.
Mm.
처음에는 누드로 그려줬어
Originally
we were painted nude.
그런 다음에
옷을 그려넣었어
But I had him add clothes,
'cause I thought
이성애적 관계에 괜한
소문을 내고 싶지 않아서
it was an unnecessary challenge
to our heterosexuality.
잘했어
Yeah, good call.
혹시라도 네 생각이 바뀌면
But if you ever change
your mind, all it would take
비눗물이랑
스폰지만 있으면 돼
is some warm, soapy water
and a couple of sponges.
그림 얘기를 하는 거지?
You're talking about
the painting, right?
그렇지
Sure.
사람 살려
SHELDON:
Help! Somebody help!
무슨 일이야?
What happened?
뭐가 있는지 보려고 했는데
머리가 안 빠져
I was trying to see what was
in here and my head got stuck.
그런 짓은 왜 했어?
Why would you do that?
과학적 호기심이라고
It's called
scientific curiosity!
버터나 갖고 와
Now go get butter.
기다려
Hang in there.
금방 올게
I'll be right back.
공대언니 블로그
http://tbbt.tistory.com
== sync, corrected by elderman ==